# **Keenan Jones**

Chicago, IL | 312-757-9548 | keenanjones210@gmail.com Github | Medium | personal portfolio/website URL | Linkedin

## **Software Engineer**

Full Stack Web Developer specializing in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React Redux. I spent six years as a massage therapist both as an employee and business owner. Looking to make a career change, I discovered web development. The enjoyment of coding and the creative outlet it provides made it clear this was the path for me. Possessing strong skills in problem-solving, customer service and communication, I'm able to convey complex issues to both technical and non-technical audiences. Highly energized by teamwork and collaboration.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Git, Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, SASS

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# ShoutRandomly - Github

A social media app; follow other users, create posts and edit profiles.

- Integration of image uploading with Active storage.
- Linked Material UI with React for simple client interface.
- Assembled RESTful design of database to organize information from server to client.

# Weather App Widget - Github

A weather display app; search based on zip code or city.

- Capitalized on React's lifecycle methods to conditionally render components.
- Utilized openweathermap API to pull and parse data on weather from across the globe.
- Managed font, images and palette with Material UI withStyles for design flexibility.

### Day21- Github

An app that is a twist on an to-do list.

- Produced API functionality with Ruby on Rails MVC pattern for data storage, simple requests and using Serializers.
- Implemented user interface employing React and Redux with Material UI for styling.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Owner, Oasis Theory, Chicago, IL

4/2014 - Present

- Assessed client's issues and created health routines for clients to become healthier.
- Collaborated with clients to help them accomplish their goals.
- Researched client's physical issues with external healthcare professionals to educate clients.

## Massage Therapist, Evolution Spine and Sport, Evanston, IL

5/2018 - 11/2019

- Communicated with internal and external healthcare professionals to improve client's current health routine.
- Assisted with the marketing strategy for the Massage Department.
- Executed the massage portion of the client's health regimen.

### **EDUCATION**

## Flatiron School, Chicago, IL

1/ 2020 - 4/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript immersive program

### Atlanta School of Massage Therapy, Atlanta, GA

11/2013 - 06/2014

Neuromuscular Therapy Certification Sport Therapies Certification

**Deep Tissue Certification** 

#### Oakton Community College, Skokie, IL

1//2015 - 12/ 2015

Coursework completed towards an Associate's Degree in Biology